Preliminary Guide to the Field Education Program Records, 1926 - 1971 UA.19.03.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Field Education Program records
1926 - 1971
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Divinity School. Field Education Program
UA.19.03.0001
4.5 Linear Feet
The Field Education Program administers a full-time summer term and a part-time academic term placements of divinity and church ministries graduate students. The Program began in 1926 under the supervision of Prof. Jesse M. Ormond, but its origins may lie in James B. Duke's donations for assisting rural N.C. churches starting around 1915. The Summer Preaching Program, as it was first known, was administered by the School of Religion in cooperation with the Rural Church Section of The Duke Endowment. Administrative records from the Field Education Program of the Duke University Divinity School. The records include correspondence and reports, 1926-1971, and administrative files, 1960-1971, documenting primarily clinical training programs. English.
3000 Items
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Field Education Program Records were received by the University Archives as transfers in 1956-2004.
Historical Note
The Field Education Program administers a full-time summer term and a part-time academic term placements of divinity and church ministries graduate students. The Program began in 1926 under the supervision of Prof. Jesse M. Ormond, but its origins may lie in James B. Duke's donations for assisting rural N.C. churches starting around 1915. The Summer Preaching Program, as it was first known, was administered by the School of Religion in cooperation with the Rural Church Section of The Duke Endowment.
Collection Overview
Administrative records from the Field Education Program of the Duke University Divinity School. The records include correspondence and reports, 1926-1971, and administrative files, 1960-1971, documenting primarily clinical training programs.
Theology -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- North Carolina; Pastoral theology -- Study and teaching; Duke Endowment; Duke University. Divinity School. Field Education Program; Duke University. Divinity School. Field Education Program; Ormond, Jesse Marvin, 1878-; Duke University. Divinity School. Summer Preaching Program
- Correspondence, 1926-1965
  Scope and Contents note
  Primarily administrative correspondence about the program and placement of the students. The bulk of the correspondence is from Prof. J.M. Ormond until 1948 and arranged chronologically.
  - 1926 (Box 1)
  - 1927 (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - 1928 (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - 1929 (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - 1930 (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - 1931 (3 folders) (Box 1)
  - 1932 (Box 1)
  - 1933 (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - 1934 (Box 1)
  - 1935 (Box 1)
  - 1936, A-L (Box 1)
  - 1936, M-W (Box 1)
  - 1937, A-L (Box 1)
  - 1937, M-W (Box 1)
  - 1938, A-G (Box 1)
  - 1938, H-M (Box 1)
  - 1938, N-W (Box 1)
  - 1939 (Box 1)
  - 1940 (Box 1)
  - 1941 (Box 1)
  - 1942 (4 folders) (Box 1)
  - 1943 (Box 2)
  - 1945 (Box 2)
  - 1946 (Box 2)
  - 1947 (2 folders with Edward F. Smith) (Box 2)
  - 1948 (Box 2)
  - 1953 (Box 2)
  - 1954 (Box 2)
  - 1956 (Box 2)
  - 1957 (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - 1965 (2 folders) (Box 2)
- Reports, 1927-1959
  Program reports, lists of placements, and related materials submitted to the Program director. Includes some student reports. Arranged chronologically.
  - 1927 (Box 2)
  - 1928 (Box 2)
  - 1929 (Box 2)
  - 1930 (Box 2)
  - 1931 (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - 1932 (Box 2)
  - 1933 (Box 2)
  - 1934 (Box 2)
  - 1935 (Box 2)
  - 1936 (Box 2)
  - 1937 (Box 2)
  - 1938 (2 folders, including student questionnaire) (Box 2)
  - 1939 (2 folders, including student questionnaire) (Box 2)
  - 1940 (Box 2)
  - 1941 (Box 2)
  - 1942 (Box 2)
  - 1947 (Box 2)
  - 1948 (Box 2)
  - 1951 (Box 2)
  - 1952 (Box 2)
  - 1953 (Box 2)
  - 1954 (Box 2)
  - 1955 (Box 2)
  - 1956 (Box 2)
  - 1957 (Box 2)
  - 1958 (Box 2)
  - 1959 (Box 2)
- Administrative Files, 1961-1971
  Scattered program administrative files including records from summer clinics and training as well as materials pertaining to the Student Field Work Association.
  - Summer Clinics
    - 1961-1962 (Box 3)
    - 1963 (Box 3)
    - 1964 (Box 3)
    - 1965 (Box 3)
    - 1966 (Box 3)
    - 1967 (Box 3)
    - 1968 (Box 3)
    - 1969 (Box 3)
  - Dan Shores files, 1969-1971 (Box 3)
  - Student Field Work Association, 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - Supervision, pastoral training, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Parish clinical training, circa 1970 (Box 3)